Guide to the Allegheny Observatory Records, 1850-1977 UA.5.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence of Directors/Acting Directors, 1850-1977; I.
  - Frank Schlesinger, 1899-1920, 1907; 6.
    Frank Schlesinger was Director from 1905-1920. Originally from Yerkes Observatory in Williams Bay, Wisconsin, Schlesinger was also president of the American Astronomical Society. His main research interest was the improvement of parallax measurements, a method of determining the distances to stars. The results of his investigations are world-renowned and he was considered an authority in that area of research. On the afternoon of Wednesday, August 28, 1912, the new observatory (Mr. Billquist was the chief architect) was dedicated and presented to the University of Pittsburgh. In the fall of 1907 Mrs. Christopher Lyman Magee donated funds to the Observatory for the purpose of establishing a publication for the research conducted by the Observatory which had been scattered throughout a variety of scientific periodicals. The first volume of the Allegheny Observatory came out in 1912 under the editorship of Frank Schlesinger. In 1920 Schlesinger left to assume the directorship of Yale Observatory.
    - Ad (Box 15, Folder 351)
    - Ai-Al (Box 15, Folder 352)
    - American A (Box 15, Folder 353-355)
    - American I-Bak (Box 15, Folder 356)
    - Barn (Box 15, Folder 357-358)
    - Barn-Bon (Box 15, Folder 359)
    - Bos (Box 15, Folder 360-365)
    - Boy-Bra (Box 15, Folder 366)
    - Bre-By (Box 15, Folder 367)
    - Cam (Box 15, Folder 368)
    - Can-Cu (Box 15, Folder 369)
    - Da-Di (Box 15, Folder 370)
    - Do-Ed (Box 15, Folder 371)
    - Ei-Fow (Box 15, Folder 372)
    - Fox (Box 15, Folder 373-375)
    - Fra-Fro (Box 16, Folder 376)
    - Fro (Box 16, Folder 377-378)
    - Fro-G (Box 16, Folder 379)
    - Hal (Box 16, Folder 380-383)
    - Har-Hy (Box 16, Folder 384)
    - In-Kaj (Box 16, Folder 385)
    - Kap (Box 16, Folder 386-387)
    - Kay-Le (Box 16, Folder 388)
    - Li-McD (Box 16, Folder 389)
    - McK-Ma (Box 16, Folder 390)
    - Mea (Box 16, Folder 391)
    - Mec-Mi (Box 16, Folder 392)
    - Na (Box 16, Folder 393)
    - Ne (Box 16, Folder 394)
    - Ni-Ph (Box 16, Folder 395)
    - Pic (Box 16, Folder 396-400)
    - Pic (Box 17, Folder 401-403)
    - Pic-Roy (Box 17, Folder 404)
    - Ru (Box 17, Folder 405-406)
    - St. F-Sta (Box 17, Folder 407)
    - Ste-Tay (Box 17, Folder 408)
    - Th (Box 17, Folder 409)
    - Ti-Tr (Box 17, Folder 410)
    - Tu (Box 17, Folder 411)
    - U.S. (Box 17, Folder 412)
    - Va-Wan (Box 17, Folder 413)
    - War (Box 17, Folder 414)
    - We-Wo (Box 17, Folder 415)
    - Y-Z (and University Correspondence) (Box 17, Folder 416)
    - Correspondence from AIS/Yale University Project
      General note
      This portion of the collection was microfilmed by the Curator in History of Physics of the American Institute of Physics. The correspondence, ranging from 1905 through 1941, held by both the Archives Service Center and the Yale University Library, was microfilmed as part of the project, Sources for History of Modern Astrophysics and is available as ais 81:6 microfilm.
      - Abbot (Smithsonian) (Box 17a, Folder 1)
      - Acker, Louis (Western University)
      - Adams, C.E. (Lick Observatory)
      - Adams, E.
      - Adams Express
      - Adams, Walter (Mt. Wilson Solar Observatory) (Box 17a, Folder 2)
      - Adlers, Cyrius (Smithsonian) (Box 17a, Folder 3)
      - Aiken Co.
      - Air Service War Dept.
      - Aitken, R.G. (Lick Observatory), 1905-1911
      - Aitken, R.G. (Lick Observatory), 1912-1915 (Box 17a, Folder 4)
      - Aitken, R.G. (Lick Observatory), 1916-1918 (Box 17a, Folder 5)
      - Albrecht, S. (Astronomical Observatory - Argentina) (Box 17a, Folder 6)
      - Alexander Bros.
      - Observatoire di Alger.
      - Allegheny Co. Light Co.
      - Allegheny Heating Co.
      - Allegheny Observatory
      - Allen, Frances (Box 17a, Folder 7)
      - Allen, Leah (Wellesley College)
      - Allritson, Alice (Nantucket Maria Mitchell Assoc.)
      - Alter, Dinsmore (Allegheny Observatory), 1909-1910
      - Alter, Dinsmore (Allegheny Observatory), 1911-1912 (Box 17a, Folder 8)
      - Alter, Dinsmore (Allegheny Observatory), 1913 (Box 17a, Folder 9)
      - Alter, Dinsmore (Allegheny Observatory), 1914-1919 (Box 17a, Folder 10)
      - Aluminum Rectifiers Co. (Box 17a, Folder 11)
      - Ambrose, Fred
      - American Astronomical Society
      - American Electrical Heater Co. (Box 17a, Folder 12)
      - American Express Co.
      - American Shipping Co.
      - American Warming and Ventilating
      - Ames, J. S. (Johns Hopkins University)
      - Ames, M. (Chemical Works)
      - Ankrom, Anna
      - Anderson, A.H.
      - Anderson, J. A. (Johns Hopkins University)
      - Apparatus on Loan
      - Appleton (D.) and Co.
      - Arbuthnot, Th. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Archenold, F.S. (Treptow - Sternwarte) (Box 17a, Folder 13)
      - Archiv.
      - Aretin
      - Armstrong. (Treasury Dept.)
      - Arnaud, J.J.
      - Asthus (Box 17a, Folder 14)
      - Astronomical and Astrophysical Society of America
      - Astronomical Journal
      - Astronomical Society of Wales
      - Atlantic Refining Co.
      - Azearate, T. (de Institute and Observatory of Marina of San Fernando) (Box 17a, Folder 15)
      - Backlund, O. (Observatory Fulkowa, Russia)
      - Bacon, Robert
      - Bailey, Frank K.
      - Bailey, Solon S. (Harvard)
      - Baillaud, B. (Paris Observatory) (Box 17a, Folder 16)
      - Baird Machinery Co.
      - Baker Office Furniture
      - Baker, Robert H. Amherst Observatory, 1906-1910
      - Baker, Robert H. Amherst Observatory, 1911 (Box 17a, Folder 17)
      - Baker, Robert H. Amherst Observatory, 1912-1919 (Box 17a, Folder 18)
      - Baker and Taylor Co. (Box 17a, Folder 19)
      - Baldwin, H. A. (YMCA)
      - Bane, Herman H. (War Dept.)
      - Barber, Ethel F. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Barnard, E.E. (Yerkes), 1904-1910 (Box 17a, Folder 20)
      - Barnard, E.E. (Yerkes), 1911-1913 (Box 17a, Folder 21)
      - Barnard, E.E. (Yerkes), 1914 (Box 17a, Folder 22)
      - Barnard, E.E. (Yerkes), 1915-1919 (Box 17a, Folder 23)
      - Barr, G.M. (British Astronomical Assoc.) (Box 17a, Folder 24)
      - Barrett, Storrs B. (Yerkes)
      - Barritt, Leon (Monthly Evening Sky Map)
      - Barrows, Albert (American Assoc. for Advancement of Sciences)
      - Bartberger, C.M.
      - Barth, Johanna (Box 17a, Folder 25)
      - Bartlett, H.N. (Westinghouse)
      - Bauer, L.A. (Carnegie Institute of Washington)
      - Beal, A.F. (U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey) (Box 17b, Folder 1)
      - Bealor, John T. (Box 17b, Folder 2)
      - Bucher, Jacob, F. (Waynesburg College)
      - Bellows, John
      - Belopolsky, A. (Sternwarte)
      - Benjamin, Marcus (U.S. National Museum)
      - Bentabal, Horacio (Engineer of Mines and Law, Madrid)
      - Bentley, E.A. (Pittsburgh Fire Extinguisher Co.)
      - Biddle, James G. (Box 17b, Folder 3)
      - Biesbroeck, G.
      - Bigalow, Ralph K.
      - Bigelow, Edward F.
      - Bigelow, Harriet W. (Smith College Observatory) (Box 17b, Folder 4)
      - Billings (New York Public Library)
      - Billquist, T. E.
      - Birbirish, A.
      - Black, A. and C.
      - Blair, G.B. (Washburn College, Morningside College)
      - Blarcom (Box 17b, Folder 5)
      - Block, Dorothy
      - Blum, Louis P. (W.G. Wilkins co.)
      - Boggs and Buhl
      - Bohlin, K.
      - Bond, J. L. (Box 17b, Folder 6)
      - Bower, Ernest Clare (U.S. Naval Observatory)
      - Borgmann, Emil
      - Borst, G. W. (The Electric Club)
      - Boss, Benjamin (Dudley Observatory), 1908-1913
      - Boss, Benjamin (Dudley Observatory), 1914-1920 (Box 17b, Folder 7)
      - Boss, Lewis (Carnegie Institution) (Box 17b, Folder 8)
      - Bouardi, J.
      - Boudin, Samuel
      - Bouesley, George T. (Engineer's Society)
      - Bowes, Homer
      - Bowie, William (Dept. of Labor and Commerce)
      - Brand, A. (Box 17b, Folder 9)
      - Brasch, F. E.
      - Brashear, John A.
      - Brashear, John A. Co., Ltd., 1906-1908 (Box 17b, Folder 10)
      - Brashear, John A. Co., Ltd., 1909-1910 (Box 17b, Folder 11)
      - Brown, Charles O. (Mellon Institute) (Box 17b, Folder 12)
      - Brown, G.W. (Yale University)
      - Brown, (Morris and Co.)
      - Bruns
      - Buchanan, J.S.
      - Burger, William J.
      - Burke, George (Dept. of Public Works)
      - Burns, Kievin (Dept. of Commerce) (Box 17b, Folder 13)
      - Burroughs Adding Machine Co.
      - Butler, C.P. (Solar Physics Observatory, Cambridge)
      - Byrd, Mary E. (Smith College Observatory)
      - Cadmus, W.R.
      - Callery, J.D. (Pittsburgh Railway Co.) (Box 17b, Folder 14)
      - Calvert, Mary R. (Yerkes)
      - Cambridge Philosophical Society
      - Cameron, M. (Curtiss Aeroplanes and Motors, Ltd.)
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1904-1906
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1907-1909 (Box 17b, Folder 15)
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1910 (Box 17b, Folder 16)
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1911-1912 (Box 17b, Folder 17)
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1913 (Box 17b, Folder 18)
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1914 (Box 17b, Folder 19)
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1915 (Box 17b, Folder 20)
      - Campbell, W.W. (Lick Observatory), 1916-1919 (Box 17b, Folder 21)
      - Canada (Astronomical Society of) (Box 17b, Folder 22)
      - Cannon, Annie J. (Harvard College Observatory)
      - Cannon, J.B. (Ottawa Observatory) (Box 17b, Folder 23)
      - Cape of Good Hope Royal Observatory
      - Cargill, J.F.
      - Carlin, Thomas H.
      - Carmalt, Alice M. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Carnegie Foundation for Advancement of Teaching
      - Carnegie Institute of Technology (Box 17b, Folder 24)
      - Carnegie Institute of Washington
      - Carnegie, Louise W.
      - Carnegie Steel Co.
      - Carnegie Technical Schools
      - Carson and White Co. (Box 17b, Folder 25)
      - Cater Electric Co.
      - Carus, Paul (The Monist - The Open Court)
      - Casey, Rev. Walter D. (St. Patrick's Rectory)
      - Cattell, J. McKeen (Popular Science Monthly) (Box 17b, Folder 26)
      - Central District and Printing Telegraph Co.
      - Challinor, William (Box 17b, Folder 27)
      - Chance Bros. And Co., Ltd.
      - Chance, F. L. (Yale University)
      - Chandler, C.F. (Columbia University)
      - Chant, C.A. (University of Toronto) (Box 17b, Folder 28)
      - Chateau Freres and Cie
      - Chevreuse Observatory (Box 17b, Folder 29)
      - Chollon, L.
      - Church
      - Civera University of Ebro
      - E. Howard Clock Co., 1905
      - E. Howard Clock Co., 1906-1909 (Box 17b, Folder 30)
      - Coast Survey (Box 17b, Folder 31)
      - Coblentz, W.W. (Box 17b, Folder 32)
      - Coe College
      - Cohn, Fritz (Pecher Institute)
      - Coleman, George
      - Columbia University
      - Compton, Alfred G. (College of the City of New York)
      - Comstock, George C. (MIT Astronomical and Astrophysical Society) (Box 17b, Folder 33)
      - Cocke, F. and Sons
      - Cooper, W.J.
      - Cortie, Rev. A.L. (Stonyhurst College) (Box 17b, Folder 34)
      - Concrete Steel Construction Co.
      - Cotsworth, M.E. (Direct Calculators)
      - Cottam, Vincent W.
      - Cowperthwaite, M.F. (U.S. Senate)
      - Cox, Harry w. Ltd.
      - Coyne, John F.
      - Cramer Dry Plate Co. (Box 17b, Folder 35)
      - Craven and Jackson
      - Craver, Harrison A. (Carnegie Library)
      - Crawford, Nettie J.
      - Crerar (John) Library
      - Cresson (George V.) Co.
      - Crew, Henry (Northwestern University) (Box 17c, Folder 1)
      - Crommelin, A.C.D. (Royal Observatory)
      - Cross, Charles P. (MIT)
      - Crypt
      - Cummings, Edith E. (Lick Observatory)
      - Cummons, J.W.
      - Cunningham, John W.
      - Curtis, Heber D. (Lick Observatory) (Box 17c, Folder 2)
      - Curtiss, Ralph H. (Lick - Detroit Observatory - Allegheny Observatory), 1905-1908 (Box 17c, Folder 3)
      - Curtiss, Ralph H. (Lick - Detroit Observatory - Allegheny Observatory), 1909-1919 (Box 17c, Folder 4)
      - Cushing, C.B. (Frick and Lindsay Co.) (Box 17c, Folder 5)
      - Customs Treasury Dept.
      - Dalby (R.H.) and Co.
      - Daniel, Laccheus (Princeton University)
      - Danifot (University of California) (Box 17c, Folder 6)
      - Danler and Cie
      - Danner, F.J., Jr.
      - Data
      - Davidson, George (University of California) (Box 17c, Folder 7)
      - Davis, Alice E.
      - Davis, Herman S. (International Geodetic Assoc.)
      - Davis, John K. (Box 17c, Folder 8)
      - Davis, K.E. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Davis, Raymond C. (University of Michigan)
      - Davis, Robert L. (Westinghouse)
      - Davis, W.M.
      - Day, Arthur L. (National Academy of Science) (Box 17c, Folder 9)
      - Day, David F.
      - Day, George Parmly (Yale University)
      - Deans of the University (University of Pittsburgh), 1913
      - Deans of the University (University of Pittsburgh), 1913 (Box 17c, Folder 10)
      - Deans of the University (University of Pittsburgh), 1914 (Box 17c, Folder 11)
      - Dempster, A. (Box 17c, Folder 12)
      - Denison University
      - Denton (Joseph Horne Co.)
      - Derlodge
      - Detroit Publishing Co.
      - Dewey, John (Columbia University)
      - Diden, J. Gordon
      - Diks, A.W.
      - Doberck, W.
      - Dodge, Otis
      - Dormtous, Charles (Westinghouse Electric)
      - Dodd, L.E. (Bureau of Standards)
      - Doolittle, C.L. (American Philosophical Society) (Box 17c, Folder 13)
      - Doolittle, Eric (University of Pennsylvania)
      - Doubleday-Hill Electric Co. (Box 17c, Folder 14)
      - Douglass, A.E. (University of Arizona) (Box 17c, Folder 15)
      - Downs, Louis (the Associated Charities of Pittsburgh)
      - Dudley, P.H. (New York Central and Hudson River Rail Road Co.)
      - Dugan, Raymond S. (Princeton University Observatory)
      - Duncan, J.C. (Box 17c, Folder 16)
      - Duncan, Robert K. (Mellon Institute of Industrial Research)
      - Du Rig, A.H.
      - Dwyer, Michael D.
      - Dyson, F.W. (Royal Observatory of Edinburgh)
      - Eastman Kodak Co. (Box 17c, Folder 17)
      - Ebert, A.G. (Technological Branch - U.S. Geological Survey)
      - Eckls, F.H. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Eddington, A.S. (Observatory Cambridge)
      - Eder Construction Co., 1906 (Box 17c, Folder 18)
      - Eder Construction Co., 1909 (Box 17c, Folder 19)
      - Edinburgh (Royal Observatory) (Box 17c, Folder 20)
      - Edward, George Co.
      - Eggers, Edward E. (Carnegie Library)
      - Eichelberger, W.S. (U.S. Naval Observatory)
      - Eimer and Amend (Box 17c, Folder 21)
      - Electric Storage Battery Co. (Box 17c, Folder 22)
      - Elston, Catherine (Western University of Pennsylvania) (Box 17c, Folder 23)
      - Engelman, Wilhelm
      - Equiley, John (College of the City of New York)
      - Evens, P.B. (University of Cincinnati)
      - Excelsior Diary (Box 17c, Folder 24)
      - Fagginger, A.C.
      - Fales, E.N.
      - Farrington, R.P. (School of Mines - University of Pittsburgh)
      - Faulkner, Richard B. (Alumni Assoc. of Columbia University)
      - Faunce, M.D. (Republic Iron and Steel Co.) (Box 17c, Folder 25)
      - Favaro International Astronomical Station of Carloforte
      - Finley, John H. (College of the City of New York)
      - Finndlick, E. Finlay
      - Board of Fire Underwriters
      - Fisher, G.C.
      - Fisher, Henry (Standard Underground Cable Co.)
      - Fitchett, H.W.
      - Fleming, George T.
      - Fleming, Williamina P. (Harvard College Observatory)
      - Flint, A.S. (Washburn Observatory University of Wisconsin) (Box 17c, Folder 26)
      - Flowtow, A.
      - Fock, Buchhandlung Gustav
      - Fowler, A. (Royal College of Science)
      - Fowler, Mary (Vassar College)
      - Fox, Phillip (Northwestern University), 1908-1911 (Box 17c, Folder 27)
      - Fox, Phillip (Northwestern University), 1912-1913 (Box 17c, Folder 28)
      - Fox, Phillip (Northwestern University), 1914 (Box 17c, Folder 29)
      - Fox, Phillip (Northwestern University), 1919-1920 (Box 17c, Folder 30)
      - French, H.W. Co. (Box 17c, Folder 31)
      - Fric, Josef and Jan
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), 1904-1907 (Box 17c, Folder 32)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), 1908-1909 (Box 17c, Folder 33)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), 1910 (Box 17c, Folder 34)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), 1911 (Box 17c, Folder 35)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), January-February 1911 (Box 17d, Folder 1)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), March-April 1911 (Box 17d, Folder 2)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), May-December 1911 (Box 17d, Folder 3)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), 1912-1913 (Box 17d, Folder 4)
      - Frost, A.E. (Western University of Pennsylvania), 1914 (Box 17d, Folder 5)
      - Frost, Edwin B. (Yerkes)
      - The Fullman Co. (Box 17d, Folder 6)
      - Fulmer, Elmer E.
      - Furness, Caroline E. (Vassar College Observatory)
      - Gaertner, William and Co., 1905-1913 (Box 17d, Folder 7)
      - Gaertner, William and Co., 1914-1920 (Box 17d, Folder 8)
      - Gale, Henry (University of Chicago) (Box 17d, Folder 9)
      - Gallo. (National Astronomical Observatory)
      - Gamble, A. (Sidney H.S.)
      - Gauthier - Villars
      - Gazetter Times (Pittsburgh)
      - Genova (R. Instituto Idrografico)
      - National Geographic Society
      - Geophysical (Box 17d, Folder 10)
      - George, Rev. W. (Henry Geneva College)
      - Gerish (James H. Rhodes and Co.)
      - German Club of Pittsburgh
      - Gill, David (Box 17d, Folder 11)
      - Gillespie, F.D.
      - Githeng, C.E. (Franklin College)
      - Gluncey, A. Estelle
      - Golden and Crick
      - Gopes, F.
      - Gosden, Thomas (Western Union Telegraph Co.)
      - Goulandris, E. (National Observatory of Athens)
      - Graduate Council of the University of Pittsburgh (Box 17d, Folder 12)
      - Graduate Council of the University of Pittsburgh, 1912 (Box 17d, Folder 13)
      - Graduate Council of the University of Pittsburgh, 1913 (Box 17d, Folder 14)
      - Graduate Council of the University of Pittsburgh, 1914 (Box 17d, Folder 15)
      - Graduate Council of the University of Pittsburgh, 1916 (Box 17d, Folder 16)
      - Graduate Council of the University of Pittsburgh, 1917 (Box 17d, Folder 17)
      - Graham, Ben G. (The High School, Greensburg, PA) (Box 17d, Folder 18)
      - Gray, B. (War Dept.)
      - Green, Henry J.
      - Green, Stephen Co.
      - Greenwood and Sons
      - Grney
      - Grosjean, Charles
      - Grossmann, E. (Box 17d, Folder 19)
      - Gundersen, May
      - Gunnell, L. (Smithsonian Institution)
      - W. and L. E. Gurley
      - Guthnick, P.
      - Hadley (Yale University)
      - Haeny, M.
      - Hagen, J.G. (Specola Vaticana) (Box 17d, Folder 20)
      - Hall, Arthur W. (Scientific Co.)
      - Hale, George E. (Mt. Wilson) (Box 17d, Folder 21)
      - Halsapple, F.F. (Juniata College) (Box 17d, Folder 22)
      - Hamerschlag (Carnegie Technical Schools)
      - Hamilton, C.H. (Rasner and Dinger Co.)
      - Hammer Dry Plate Co.
      - Hammond, John (U.S. Naval Observatory)
      - Hamy, M.
      - Handgrove, M.R. (Pennsylvania Railroad)
      - Harmon (St. John's College)
      - The Harmsworth Encyclopedia
      - Harper, W.E. (Dept. of Interior)
      - Harris, L.H. (School of Engineering, University of Pittsburgh)
      - Harris (Philip) and Co., Ltd.
      - Harper, W.E. (Dept. of Interior) (Box 17d, Folder 23)
      - Hartmann (Astrophysikalishes Observatory, Potsdam)
      - Hartwig
      - Harwood, M.
      - Hassel, Karl (School of Eng., University of Pittsburgh)
      - Hasselberg, B.
      - Hastings, Charles (Yale University) (Box 17d, Folder 24)
      - Haussman, K. (Box 17d, Folder 25)
      - Hawkers, Julia
      - Hawkesworth, Alan S. (Carnegie Library)
      - Hayford, John F. (Northwestern University)
      - Haynes, E.S. (Laws Observatory)
      - Hays, S. Mimis (American Philosophical Society)
      - Hendrick, Henry B. (Nautical Almanac Office)
      - Heger, Mary Lee (University of California) (Box 17d, Folder 26)
      - Henck, J.B.
      - Hendrickson - Maytham Co.
      - Henroteau, F. (Lick Observatory)
      - Hepperger
      - Herda, C.
      - Herr, E.M. (Westinghouse)
      - Herron, J.W.
      - Hertzsprang, Rjnar (Box 17d, Folder 27)
      - Hildebrandson, H.H. (Box 17d, Folder 28)
      - Higer (A.), Ltd.
      - Hinchman, Lydia S. (Maria Mitchell Assoc., Osceola)
      - Hinks (The Observatory, Cambridge)
      - Hirayama, Shin (University of Tokyo)
      - Hirsch, William (American Steel and Wire Co.)
      - Histaling, S. (Box 17d, Folder 29)
      - Hobe, A. (Lick)
      - Holden, E.S. (West Point Military Academy)
      - Holder, F. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Holland, W.
      - Hollis, H.P. (Royal Observatory)
      - Holmes, George S. (First Methodist Episcopal Church)
      - N. Holmes and Sons
      - Holmes, Rachel
      - Holmes, Samuel
      - Hood, W.K. (Duquesne Fireproofing Co.) (Box 17d, Folder 30)
      - Hoogewerff, J.A. (US Naval Observatory)
      - Hoover
      - Hopkins, L.S. (Kent State)
      - Hopkins, M.M. (Smith College Observatory)
      - Hough, S.S. (Royal Obs., Cape of Good Hope)
      - Howard, F.B. (U.S. Naval Observatory)
      - Hudson, Charles J. (Amherst College Observatory) (Box 17e, Folder 1)
      - Huggins
      - Humphreys, W.J. (U.S. Weather Bureau Office)
      - Hundred (American Assoc. for Advancement of Science)
      - Huntington (Wells- Fargo Co.)
      - Hussey, W.J. (Detroit Observatory) (Box 17e, Folder 2)
      - Hutchinson, C.F. (National Research Council) (Box 17e, Folder 3)
      - Hutchinson, Robert
      - Ihinohe, Naozo (Tokyo Astronomical Observatory)
      - Ihlsenj, M.C. (Blairsville College)
      - Imperial Academy of Sciences of St. Petersburg
      - Innes, R.T.A. (Transvaal Observatory)
      - ION - Journal of Electronics, Astomistics, Ionology, Radioactivity and Baumchemistry (Box 17e, Folder 4)
      - Royal Instituto Idrografic
      - Italian Association for the Advancement of Science
      - Jacob and Valentin
      - Jacobs, I.W. (Northwestern mutual Life Insurance)
      - Jacoby, Harold (Columbia University)
      - Jay, Alfred H. (Syrian Protestant College Observatory) (Box 17e, Folder 5)
      - Jayne, J.L. (U.S. Naval Observatory)
      - Jeffery Manufacturing Co.
      - Jennings, F.R. (Box 17e, Folder 6)
      - Jeulsius, Louise F.
      - H.W. Johns-Manville Co.
      - Johnson, Anthony (Reed and Witting)
      - Johnston and Co.
      - Jonckhure, Robert
      - Jones (Dept. of Commerce)
      - Jordan, F.C. (Yerkes Observatory) (Box 17e, Folder 7)
      - Jursek, Carl C.
      - Kaeurpffert (Box 17e, Folder 8)
      - Kapteyn, J.C. (Mt. Wilson Solar Observatory)
      - Kauffman Bros.
      - Kayser (Box 17e, Folder 9)
      - Keating, W.A.
      - Keeler, James
      - Keen, W.W. (Philosophical Society)
      - Kehro, John
      - Kellogg, Fred (Allegheny Co. Light Co.)
      - Kennedy, J.E.
      - Keppel, T.P. (Columbia) (Box 17e, Folder 10)
      - Kester, F.E. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Ketchuny, George (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Keyser, C.J. (Columbia University)
      - King (Dominion Observatory, Harvard College Observatory)
      - Kistler, R.L. (Box 17e, Folder 11)
      - Kistner, Mark (St. Vincent College)
      - Klages, G.W.
      - Kloh, Skar. (University of Pittsburgh)
      - Klotz (Dept. of Interior)